Guide to the Charles G. Muller papers, 1914-1986
Muller, Charles G. papers, 1914-1986
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Charles G. Muller papers, 1914-1986
3788
Charles G. Muller, 1897-1987
14.5 cubic ft., 2 tape recordings.
Correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, pamphlets, notes, and audio recordings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Various items documenting the life and work of Charles G. Muller.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Journalist, author, consultant. Cornell University Class of 1918. Charles G. Muller died in 1987. In Cornell University alumni records, his middle name is George; but as an author, he styled himself Charles Geoffrey Muller or Charles G. Muller.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers of Charles G. Muller, include diaries (1914-1921) and appointment books (1922-1973) that relate to Muller's activities and attitudes; correspondence, photographs, and scrapbooks concerning his service with an American Red Cross ambulance unit in France (1917) and a trip he took around the world (1919-1920), the latter including Red Cross work in Libau, Latvia; research files for books on the War of 1812, THE PROUDEST DAY: MACDONOUGH ON LAKE CHAMPLAIN (1960) and THE DARKEST DAY: 1814, THE WASHINGTON-BALTIMORE CAMPAIGN (1963); pamphlets, notes, address lists, correspondence, and recorded speeches pertaining to his activities with Alcoholics Anonymous, Alateen, and the National Council on Alcoholism; notes and drafts of NO CORK FOR THE BOTTLE; documentation on many consulting projects, primarily in the field of fund raising; notes, drafts, correspondence, and manuscript for DEMOCRACY'S GIFT DOLLARS; and correspondence, drafts, and notes pertaining to other writing jobs. Also, material relating to Cornell University, and Muller's research material for a March 1984 CORNELL ALUMNI NEWS article "Scotty's Gold Mine," detailing the partnership of Walter Edward Scott (Death Valley Scotty) and Albert Mussey and Bessie Penniman Johnson, and their Death Valley estate, Scotty's Castle.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Muller, Charles Geoffrey, 1897-; Johnson, Albert Mussey; Johnson, Bessie Penniman; Muller, Charles Geoffrey, 1897- Darkest day: 1814, the Washington-Baltimore campaign.; Muller, Charles Geoffrey, 1897- No cork for the bottle.; Muller, Charles Geoffrey, 1897- Proudest day.; Scott, Walter Edward.; Brakeley, George A. Democracy's gift dollars.; Alateen.; Alcoholics Anonymous.; National Council on Alcoholism.; American National Red Cross.; Scotty's Castle.
Subjects:
Alcoholism.; Fund raising.; World War, 1914-1918.; Authors.; Journalists.
Places:
Death Valley (Calif.); Liepaja (Latvia).; United States--History--War of 1812.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.; Speeches.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Diaries and Datebooks, 1914-1986
Box 1
Series II. Scrapbooks, Memorabilia and Correspondence
Box 2
Series III. War of 1812 Research Materials
Boxes 3-4
Series IV. Alcoholics Anonymous
Boxes 4-6, 10
Series V. Writing Jobs
Boxes 6-9, 15-19
Series VI. Miscellany
Boxes 10-14
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Diaries and Datebooks, 1914-1986
  - "My Trip Abroad", 1914; Records events on his trip to England, Scotland, Belgium, Holland, Germany, Switzerland, and Italy. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Datebook for 1917", (no entries Jan. 5-May 16, Oct. 9 Dec. 31) Records activities while in Section 22, Norton Harjes American Red Cross Ambulance Service with the French Army. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Datebook for 1918", (no entries Jan. 1-May 20) Records drive west from Ithaca to Indiana to enlist, back to Syracuse and Ithaca, working at Treman King?s, early writing pursuits, training and service as an aviation pilot with the U.S. Naval Reserve. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Datebook for 1919", Contains accounts of activities in Pensacola, Florida, New York City, Ithaca, and at summer camp and travels in England, France, Spain and St. Nazaire. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Agenda de Bureau pour 1920", Records remainder of stay in Libau for the American Red Cross Commission to Western Russia and travels to Riga, Norway, London, the Antwerp Olympics, Nantes, the Red Sea, the Indian Ocean, China, Vietnam, Japan, Hawaii, California and East to Boston. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Daily Reminder 1921", (sporadic and usually brief entries) In New York, Ithaca and the mid-west, settled in Michigan where he was reporter and editor for the Grand Rapids Press. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Datebook, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Datebook, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Datebook, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Datebook, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Datebook, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Datebook, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Datebook, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Datebook, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Datebook, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Datebook, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Datebook, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Datebook, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Datebook, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Datebook, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Datebook, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Datebook, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Datebook, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Datebook, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Datebook, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Datebook, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Datebook, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Datebook, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Datebook, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Datebook, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Datebook, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Datebook, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Datebook, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Datebook, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Datebook, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Datebook, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Datebook, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Appointment book lists activities, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Appointment book, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Appointment book lists activities, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Appointment book, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Appointment book, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Appointment book lists activities, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Appointment book lists activities, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Appointment book lists activities, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Appointment book lists activities, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Appointment book lists activities, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Appointment book lists activities (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous papers removed from diaries., Map of Pisa, postcards, and "Fleeing from the Wrath of Europe", a pamphlet by Mrs. Charles Wentworth (1914); a postcard of a water color, pocket calendar, and a list of authors and their works (1917); photo of troops and a camp and a hotel bill (1920) from the 1918 diary; plan of Toledo, and a postcard of peasants making planks (1919) (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Address book (no date) (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Appointment books, 1974-1986 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Series II. Scrapbooks, memorabilia and correspondence
  - Cornell scrapbook, 1916-1917; Includes photos of people and buildings, pamphlets and programs. A number of items on baseball. (Box 2)
  - Photo album of American Red Cross section 22 with the French Army on the Verdun Front (1917) with key, Includes pictures of the trip over, Paris, enroute to Verdun, just behind the lines, time off, and the trip home. Also, key to photo album. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Journal of Muller?s trip around the world in 1920, Contains visiting cards, a typed journal (Sept. 8 ? Dec. 7, 1920), a story about Peking, "Adrian Acquires Confucius", written in Grand Rapids, "Peking Nights at the Play", vignettes from his trip, and his ship?s itinerary and passenger list. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "A Trip thru Europe during the summer of 1914", Collection of letters sent to his parents, George and Jennie (Hodgkinson) Muller from Europe. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "With the Red Cross in Russia. 1919-1920", 1919-1921; Documents, letters, journal entries and the Red Cross Bulletin, miscellaneous issues, June ? Nov. 1921. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Grand Rapids Press", Volume contains stories, letters to Charlie and Georgi (Georgia L. Stafroogh) Muller, whom Charlie married in 1921, signed "Kiss". n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Around the World", Aug. 1919 ? Dec. 1920, 1919-1921; Photographs of France, Spain (LaCorida, Toledo), Russia (Libau, Civilian Relief work, Riga), Reine and a few related documents and clippings. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photograph album, Contains pictures of Sweden and Norway (Bergen), Antwerp, Belgium and the Olympic games, friends, Port Said, the Suez Canal, Djibute, Colombo, Singapore, Saigon, Hong-Kong, Shanghai, Puchow, Peking, the Great Wall, Mukden, Korea (Seoul), Japan (Kioto, Mara, Nikko, Kamakura), Honolulu, San Francisco, and Mexico. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Documents, U.S. Passport, Red Cross i.d., map of the Front at Verdun, order for transport, two photographs (Muller in 1917), and miscellaneous documents related to Red Cross work. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - World War I photographs (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Navy items (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series III. War of 1812 research materials
  - British ? Chesapeake. British Names, Cochburn (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - British ? Chesapeake. British Ships, Chesapeake raids (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Benedict to Bladensburg. Battle of (Aug. 24) Bladensburg (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Navy Yard ? Alexandria (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Washington. Background. President?s house (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Washington. Invasion and capture, aftermath (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Baltimore, North Point (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Baltimore, Fort McHenry (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Newspapers, Sources (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Atrocities, Negroes (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Local color, Vermont and Champlain data (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - General Background, Peace Treaty, New Orleans (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Results and Philosophy, Caribbean (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Mediterranean, Barbary pirates (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ships, boat building (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Small boats, working ship (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Terms, navigation (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Decatur to 1803, burning of Philadelphia (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Gunboat fights, armament (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Flags, Signals. Uniforms. Distances (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "Ship Life and background," men and officers, living on ship (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Rules and Regulations, nautical talk, duels (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Theme, title, family background, historical war with France (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - James C. 1800-1801 Ganges. 1801-1803. Mac. Phila. 1803-4 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Lake Champlain. Capt. Farmer. Letters (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Congress hearing. Birthplace of Navy. Draft and Farmer letters, ideas (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Trip to Maryland with Admiral McCain ? Navy seapower (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - "Ten Americans" (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Sea power (John McCain) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Valcour (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Illustrations ? leaflets. Capt. Farmer museum (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Farmer ? Whithall (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Adventures (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fights (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Storms (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Navy ? General (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Names (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ships (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Constellation (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Constitution (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Admiral Cooper Tall. (Fort Ticonderoga Fleet) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - War of 1812 ? Names (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence - MacDonough (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence ? MacDonough (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - MacDonough (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - MacDonough ? background (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - MacDonough ? letters (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - MacDonough ? photos (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Mrs. Mac (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Political Background (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - How people lived (Discarded ? The Whitehall Times, July 1, 1976) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Booklets (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Possible characters. Macomb (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Possible characters, Navy ? army personnel (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Possible characters, C and M notes (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Eleazer Williams (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Pamphlets (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Rare book dealer?s catalogs (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Series IV. Alcoholics Anonymous
  - No Cork for the Bottle
    - John Shaw notes, Nov. 24, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Notes (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Draft (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - 1st draft, P. 1-130, Jan. 9, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - 1st draft, P. 142-295, Jan. 9, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Draft, July 13, 1973. Rewritten Nov. 7, 1973 Ch. 1-2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Draft, July 13, 1973. Rewritten Nov. 7, 1973 Ch. 3-6 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Final revision, Steven Howd Ch. 1-12, Aug. 5, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Final revision, Steven Howd Ch. 13-24, Aug. 5, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Final revision, Steven Howd Ch. 25-30, Aug. 5, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Draft, Nov. 24, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Discards, final revision (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Early draft (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Early draft (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Early draft (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Original copy from Anita Diamant, P. 1-130, Aug. 1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Original copy from Anita Diamant, P. 131-230, Aug. 1973 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Original copy from Anita Diamant, P. 231-301, Aug. 1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Profile of an Al-Anon by Jeff M., P.1-100, July 18, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Profile of an Al-Anon by Jeff M., P. 101-200, July 18, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Profile of an Al-Anon by Jeff M., P. 201-276, July 18, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Part I (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Part II (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Part III (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Part IV (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Part V (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Al-Anon
    - Notes (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Pamphlets (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Names and phones (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Guidance Westbrook (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Alateen
    - Vitam Center (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Ridgefield-Winton (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Leaflets (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Names ? phones (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Program (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - National Council on Alcoholism
    - Locals (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Mr. Jeff Muller (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous on Alcoholism
    - C.G. Muller on station KIUP, Durango, Co. Breakfast Club, Feb. 14, 1979 (Folder tr. 475)
    - C.G. Muller on A.A. Panel for Hall-Brook. Westbrook, CT radio station WMMM, 1973? (Folder tr. 476a)
- Series V. Writing Jobs
  - John Price Jones
    - Legal claim; 1950, 50th anniversary dinner (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - New York University presentations (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - N.Y.U. brochure (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - N.Y.U. correspondence (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Tuskegee Institute ? adult education (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Channel 13 WNET Memos (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Channel 13 WNET Interviews (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Channel 13 WNET Background 1 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Channel 13 WNET Present situation 2 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Channel 13 WNET Analysis of potential 3 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Channel 13 WNET Recommended procedure 4 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Channel 13 WNET Suggestions for future 5 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Channel 13 WNET Discards (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Fund raising papers, Harold J. Seymour (1956 ), Robert F. Duncan (1971), John J. Schwartz (1976), Talbot M. Malcolm (1972), Robert F. Goheen (1973), John H. Filer (1974). (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Fundraising
    - Bennington College 1958 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - The Kellogg Service, Ind. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Watson Foundation 1975 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Watson Foundation 1964 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Bishop Anderson Foundation drafts (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Articles (discarded: Life, 1975, Control of Life series) (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous articles and notes (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Bishop Anderson home. "Interviews" (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - "The Institute" (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - "The Institute" (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Philosophy (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Biddle Foundation correspondence (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Biddle Foundation reports (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Fund raising (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "The Grand Option (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Loyola U. in New Orleans (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Washington U. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Democracy's Gift Dollars
    - Titles/Plan Part 1 (Overall) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Philosophy of American Giving (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Voluntarism ? Backbone of Giving (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - The Gift dollar in Our Free Society (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Fund-Raising Patterns (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Professional Fund-raisers as catalysts. Part 2 (Particular) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Where gift Dollars Go (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Philanthropies and Philanthropists (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Corporate Philanthropy (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Government: Philanthropy?s Dynamic Partner (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Philanthropy?s Flaw, Part 3. (How to) (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Role of Professional Counsel (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Opportunism vs. Statesmanship (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Management of Money Raising (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - The Case (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Public Relations in Fund Raising (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Role of the Program Director (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Role of Program Leadership (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Identifying and Cultivating the Gift (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - The Big-Gift Approach (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Asking for the Gift Dollar (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - The Deferred Gift (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - "Bringing it All Together" (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - "The New Face of Fund Raising" (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Appendices (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Other writing jobs and connections
    - Salty comments (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Higher education (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Figures/Statistics (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Uninvited billions (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Haldane (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Haldane (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Neijelski (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Edward V. Graef (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Decision Research Corp. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Robert F. Duncan (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - David M. Church (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Donald F. Sheehan (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Chester M. Tucker (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - John Grenzebach and Assocs., Inc (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Greater NY Fund (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - United Community Funds and Cncls. Of America (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Metro (United Fund) (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Arthur Hayes - DPW (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Lucille Culliver (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Arthur H. Torrey (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Alamo (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Science Research (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Women?s World (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Foundation Histories (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Naval Institute (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Fairfield County Magazine (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Public Relations (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Howland Foundation (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Jerry Ade. Charles A. Lindbergh (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Kittiwake ? Howard Bloomfield ? education adventure (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Jim Wharton (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Clate Austin ? Montclair, N.J (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Campus films (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Friday Club (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Greenevine (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Barbara Bates (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Note Bienstock (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Career Planning book, (Haldane, Faith, Dalgren. Young Adult Career Planning, removed from collection). (Box 8, Folder 32-33)
    - Your Job Power (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Knights of the Road (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Stories for Barbara (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Cornell Frosh (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - A Cry for Help Revised 1-25-71 ch. 1-10 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - A Cry for Help Revised 1-25-71 ch. 11- (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - A Cry for Help Revised 1-25-71 ch. 2 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Cry for Help Revised 1-25-71 ch. 2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - "If You Live Long Enough," Cry for Help. Original and notes (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Part 1. Cry for Help, Reno-L.A (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Part 2. Cry for Help, L.A.-San Diego (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Part 3. Cry for Help, San Diego-Albuquerque (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Part 4. Cry for Help, Albuquerque-Maine (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - People are Wonderful 1st draft (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - People are Wonderful Ideas to use (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - People are Wonderful Ideas. Outlines (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - G.A. Brakeley & Co., Inc
    - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Speeches (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - The Book (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Brakeley III Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - The Brakely Book (Box 9, Folder 20-25)
  - Fund raising (also, books and articles)
    - Accounts worked on (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "An American Drama Act III" (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - "Are Today?s Children Different?" (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - "aviation?s Most Promising Partner" (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "Build Hope" (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - "Business Speaks up About Flying" (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "the Choate School Fund Fiftieth Anniversary Campaign" (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "Cover the Admiral" (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 9-10)
    - The Darkest Day (Box 15, Folder 11-16)
    - "Dizzy Female" (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - The Donor?s Tax Dollar" (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - "Even Before the Statue of Liberty" (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - "The Greater New York Fund Annual Report," 1951 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - "Our Flag" (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Hero of Champlain (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Hero of Two Seas including ms. and proofs (Box 15, Folder 23-34)
    - "Hobey Baker Himself" (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - "How Cannon Proves It" (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - "If This Family Knocked on Your Door What Would You Do?" (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - "Make No Little Plans" (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - "The Mary Duke Biddle Foundation 1971 The Trustees" (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Michigan Memorial-Phoenix Project (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - No Cork for the Bottle editing (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - "Our Community Raises a New Hospital Center" (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - "New York University-Bellevue Medical Center" (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence re The Proudest Day (Box 15, Folder 44-48)
    - "No Vacancies" (Christ Hospital) (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - "Sales Promotion" (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - Standard foundation presentation (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - Ten Americans and the Star Spangled Banner" (Box 15, Folder 52-53)
    - re "Tigers of the Sea" (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - "Uses of Aircraft in Industry" (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - "Valiant Women ? The Eden Hall Centenary" (Box 15, Folder 56)
    - "The Way to Lift Hundred Tons is to Lift It with Your Head!" (Box 15, Folder 57)
    - "?We? ? The Story of Achievement in Aviation" (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - "When Your Company Must Terminate Employees?" (Box 15, Folder 59)
    - "Willowmere" (Box 15, Folder 60)
    - "With Privileges Go Responsibilities" (Graham-Eckes School Fund) (Box 15, Folder 61)
    - "You, a Smith parent, can help", "Your Business has a Stake in the Smith College 75th Anniversary Fund" (Box 15, Folder 62)
    - "the Younger Generation Goes to Work" (Box 15, Folder 63)
    - Miscellany (Box 15, Folder 64)
    - The Brearley School (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Negro Colleges;" "Foundation for a Dream;" "On the Same Team" (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Metropolitan Communications Program" (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
    - Montclair, NJ (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Greater New York Fund (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - New York University (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Community Service Society (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - "Gift Dollars" (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - "The Williston Academy Second Century Campaign" (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - "Build Hope" ? Hope College case statement (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - The John Jay and Eliza Jane Watson foundation (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Notes on Field Survey for Cup and Container Inst., 1939 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Verbatim Reports on field Survey for Dixie Vortex Company, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 14)